So, Sora 2 is absolutely changing the
game when it comes to AI video. But if
you want to create great videos on the
platform, you need to know how to write
a great prompt. I have spent a ton of
time researching how the top creators on
Sora are writing prompts. Today, I'm
going to be showing you how to create
the best Sora 2 prompts possible,
ranging from simple prompts all the way
to advanced multi-step prompts where we
plan out every single second of the
shot. We'll also be covering how to add
sound effects, [music]
voiceovers, and more. all in one
structured prompt. But the one issue is
that Sora [music] 2 prompts can be so
advanced that they take a long time to
make. And who has time to be writing
prompts for every single video? That's
why if you stick around to the end of
the video, I'll be giving you access to
my custom GPT that I've trained on the
best Sora [music] 2 prompting practices
with a ton of data so that you can
quickly and easily create the best SORT
2 prompts possible by chatting with chat
GPT. So stick around to the end of the
video and check that out. It's actually
impossible to just skip right to that.
You have to watch the video as well as
like it if you want to. So, let's jump
right into things. So, let's talk about
Sora prompting best practices. [music]
If we want to create a good prompt, how
does Sora prompting even work? Prompting
can be complex and overwhelming, but
don't worry, I'm here to break it down
for you. Sora prompting uses natural
language. The types of prompts Sora 2
can accept vary, and Sora 2 is an
incredibly flexible platform. However,
[music] there's one simple formula that
all good prompts follow on Sora. This
formula goes as follows. Scene intent
plus shot composition plus lighting and
tone. [music] These three things
together make a great Sora prompt. Let's
check out what scene intent is. Scene
intent is describing the overall theme
or world that you're looking to create.
Usually, in one to three sentences,
think of this as briefing your
cinematographer. What is the viewer
looking to feel? What are you looking to
create? An example of our scene intent
could be something such as a highquality
2D anime film style cinematic realism. A
samurai woman with long white hair walks
slowly along a coastal path beside the
ocean. We get some detail about her
armor as well as some other details
about the scene. The next part of the
formula is shot composition. What is
happening in our shot? Who are our
characters and what is the action? If we
described a woman walking alongside a
path and our scene intent, what do we
want to happen in the video besides
that? Sora accepts both timestamp as
well as cutbased prompt control, meaning
that you can break a prompt into
different cuts or timestamps, which
we'll show later in the video, so that
you can have an incredible amount of
control over your Soritude prompts.
Here's an example you'll see here where
we are able to break out. Hey, the woman
walks along the path, the camera follows
smoothly behind her. We transition to
looking at the fence. Her hand touches
it and then we show a medium shot of her
face where she looks out against the
horizon and then quietly whispers, "Hey,
I'll return someday." If you'll notice
here, we can use these timestamps within
the shot composition to direct how and
when these shots happen. We'll get more
into that later. The last is lighting
and tone. We want to end with a single
paragraph that defines the scene's
overall look and feel. Lighting,
atmosphere, amore, and emotional tone.
This is what ties everything together.
And it's actually incredibly important
that we do this in every single prompt.
So, this is usually saying something
like golden late afternoon sunset with
soft shadows, dynamic ocean reflections,
details about this scene that don't
necessarily belong at the top of your
prompt, however, fit really well at the
night at the end in order to tie
everything together. Sora as a whole
right now as a video generation platform
is the best platform at understanding
and reacting to your prompt. So, it's
super important as a creator that you
understand how to use it correctly to
make the best videos possible. Now, all
of this theory is good to know, but it's
all useless unless we put it into
motion. So, if you're like me and you
learn from being hands-on, let's build a
few prompts together, step by step, so
you can see how this works. Feel free to
follow along as we build these things
together. I'll put all the prompts we
use in the description below to go into
Sora and try it out for yourself. So
let's start with prompt style one where
we're going to start easy here with
simple instructions. So for our first
video we are just going to be using text
to video and we're going to be giving
simple instructions about our scene
intent as well as our lighting and tone.
So we're going to go into Sora here. So,
for our scene intent, I am going to use
just a simple, hey, high quality 2D
anime film style. And then we're going
to do our lighting is warm and cinematic
with a late afternoon sunlight glinting
off the ocean surface with the sound of
distant waves and wind competes with the
tranquil environment. And we're going to
put all this into our prompt. This is
what it looks like here in Sora. And I'm
going to hit generate. Now, I'm going to
pause so we can listen to this with
sound. And then we'll talk over the
recording with it muted.
So, as we see here, this pretty much did
exactly what we looked for. It gave us
an anime style image of the woman
walking down the path. It had We didn't
ask for any specific cuts. We asked for
just the woman walking down the path
with the sound of the distant waves in
the background. It did that pretty much
exactly and really caught the
cinematography of the scene we were
looking to create. You could use this if
you were creating an anime as a shot
before another shot. It's not incredibly
advanced. We don't need a super complex
prop to create something like this. Now,
let's move on to prompt style number
two, our medium difficulty. Let's kick
things up a notch and start to see how
Sora can handle more complex
instructions. We know that Sora can
handle a simple shot like we just
created. However, if we want to create a
complex shot, we have 10 seconds in each
sore generation. If you're on the free
plan, you've got 12 seconds if you're on
a pro plan. Let's use every single one
of those seconds to do this correctly.
So, let's introduce the concept of cuts.
still giving Sora some freedom as to the
timing of each cut, but giving more
direction as to what we are looking for.
The next thing we're going to do is
introduce our shot composition part of
the prompt. Now, our shot composition
part is going to go in and it's going to
show exactly what we're looking for. In
cut one, we want to walk we want to
watch her walk slowly down the fence. In
cut two, we want to see the camera tilt
downward towards the rocks below. And
then in cut three, we want to see her
eyes reflecting and we want her to say,
"It's been so long." So, how you
introduce voice effects as well as sound
effects is that you put them where they
need to go in the prompt. So, if I want
her to say something such as, "It's been
so long. I'm going to put that in cut
three of this prompt." So, she says this
towards the end. If I wanted her to say
this in cut one, I would put it in cut
one. It would be more towards the
beginning. Now, I ask here for a ship
horn. And the ship horn I am putting in
cut two, but I'm also referencing this
again in the lighting and tone. My GPT I
let you know that I'll show you at the
end knows how to do all of this
automatically. Just know that specific
dialogue needs to be mentioned within
the cut. More tonal sounds or background
sounds can be mentioned in the lighting
and tone section. So let's put all of
this into Sora here and see what it
comes up with. So I'm just going to take
the prompt. I'm going to copy and paste
it here into Sora. Exactly. And I'm
going to hit create video. Okay. Let's
check out the video that Sora created
from our prompt. Remember we had our
woman walking. We wanted to see the
ocean. And then we wanted to see a
close-up of her face. And she wanted to
say, "It's been so long." Bonus points
if she says this with a dramatic anime
flare.
>> It's been so long.
>> So, that's pretty much exactly what we
asked for, right, everyone? First, she's
walking down the path. Then, we see our
waves, and then we get a close-up of her
where she says what we're asking for.
This is a simple scene, guys, with
simple interactions, but just know that
this is how you would create for text to
video complex fight scenes, crazy shots.
You'll see on the homepage, this is a
formula that allows you to do that. I'm
do a lot of anime on this channel, but
you could use this for literally
anything. You could have Jake Paul
punching people if you wanted to using
this style. This works for any type of
composition and works with my GPT, which
you can use, and I'll tell you about at
the end of the video. We've done two
texttovideo examples, and some would say
text to video is the easy way to do
things. So let's go in and let's test
out the hard style. So for prompt number
three, what we're introducing here is we
want to use image to video with adjusted
language and cuts. Now image to video
has some advantages as well as some
disadvantages when we think about
prompting on Sora. The first is that
image to video is going to allow you to
take images that you create in an
external platform. Maybe something like
a midjourney here where we've created an
image of our samurai woman here walking
down the path. And so this allows us to
take images that maybe we create in
midjourney. Maybe I go into Nano Banana
and we're creating a whole different
world here from this image. Drop a
comment on the video below if you'd like
to see a guide on how to do that. For
prompt three, what we're going to do is
that we're using image to video, but
there's a couple different things here.
We're adjusting how we're asking for
some of these things from the initial
frame. So, instead of saying the woman's
walking, we're saying the woman gently
shifts her weight, then begins walking a
few slow steps towards the fence down
the path. We have our multi-shot
composition with timestamps so it knows
exactly how long we want for each one.
And then finally, we have our lighting
and tone. So, let's go in and see how
this one did. We'll go in and take our
whole prompt here. We'll go into Sora
and we'll paste this one. And I will hit
create video.
>> It's been so long.
>> So, this is really the power of Sora,
guys. You can't prompt like this in any
other platform. This is why Sora is so
cool and why everyone's so freaking
excited about it. I'm so excited about
AI videos, everyone. If we see here the
output of the video, we have her walking
down the path like we asked for our
exact image. We had complete control
over this entire prompt. [music] We then
see we get a shot of our ocean and then
we see here and then she says our
dialogue. Exactly. We also have that
ship horn in the background. This is
incredibly cool. This is what you would
say complete control. We're using every
single part of our 10 seconds. All of
these prompts will be linked in the
description below so you can try these
things out for yourself. Just understand
that your imagination is the only limit
here. It's only going to get better in
time. Sora 3, Sora 4, we're in a wild
time, everyone. Now, hopefully you have
a better understanding of how to prompt
Sora for the best results possible.
However, there's one problem. You know,
as you can see, Sora understands those
large complex prompts, but these prompts
take a long time to write. You can have
GPT do it for you, but you would need to
let it know what you're asking for each
time. That takes time. And this is why
I've created my own custom GPT, which I
will link in the description below, that
you can use to create your own prompts.
It's 100% free and it will create
prompts that utilize all of the best
practices that we went through the video
here today easily and quickly. You can
go into this GPT and you can ask for any
different type of prompts. This GPT is
trained on the best practices possible.
You can see here it gave us exactly what
we are looking for in the same different
style of prompts that we created in this
video. All in one second, completely
unscripted. I just did this right now. I
will constantly be updating and refining
this GPT. I'll probably put cling into
this thing next. I'll probably put
midjourney in here as well at some
point. Just want to provide the best
stuff for you all. So, go ahead and
check this out. It's in the description.
And thank you so much for watching to
this point so that you can get this. I
know you didn't just skip to this point,
right? That I mean that does that
wouldn't even work, right? You can't
even do that. I think YouTube blocks
you. If you did do that, like the video.
That'd be awesome. That'd be great. I'd
love that. Anyways, guys, thank you so
much for watching. If you enjoy my
content or find value in this video,
please drop a like on the video. That
helps it get out to more people. And
drop me a sub if you enjoy my content.
I'm trying to get to 500 subs by the end
of the year. That would make me so happy
if we could do that. But honestly, it
just makes me happy making these videos
for you all, interacting with you all. I
hope you all see some value in this.
Anyways, I hope you all have a fantastic
rest of the day and I'll see you all on
the next one. Peace.